GOKUL GOPAKUMAR

Lead Data Analyst

Address KOCHI, India 682303

Phone +919656381085

E-mail gokulthottupuram@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gokulgryptos/

Perceptive and logical data analyst with proven ability to communicate with both technical professionals and end users to identify and translate business requirements. Offering 4+ years of experience in driving data accuracy and integrity through different roles. Proven ability to build and lead teams of talented professionals to develop valuable process solutions to meet business objectives.

Skills

Critical Thinking & Problem Solving	•••••
Python	••••
SQL	••••
Excel	••••
PySpark	••••
Power BI	••••
Project Management	••••
A/B Testing	••••

Work History

2020-05 - Current

Lead Data Analyst

Prevalent AI India Private Ltd, Kochi, Kerala

1. Cyber Exposure Analytics in Insurance Domain

- Leading Insurance domain project (B2B) for solving silent cyber exposure in general and specialty market insurance policies
- Interpret 6 real world cyber incident scenarios and turn into information which can be easily assimilated and interpreted for insurance use cases
- · Leading design, development, implementation and maintenance of analytical solution with 100+ users
- Having experience on applying **A/B testing experiments** as part of quality improvement process.
- Identify, analyses, and interpret trends in happening in industry and making the system up to date to handle real life scenarios (Eg: Ukraine war scenario help client to save \$10+ millions)
- Used **Applied Business statistics** like **regressions models** and other techniques throughout the journey.

· Leading team as Client Delivery Lead

Skills: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplot, Seaborn, Excel, Agile, JIRA,

Confluence, SQL, Project Management

2. Security Data Science platform - Cyber Security

- Leading a 15 member team of cross functional departments including developers, data scientists and analyst, QA, designers and DevOps to deliver a cyber product to MNC
- Data we processing is from 170+ regions and 410K+ users around globe.
- Applying Data Science knowledge and expertise to help companies understand, deploy and support most advanced security solutions.
- Leveraged text, charts and graphs to communicate findings in understandable format.
- Developed complex dashboard and reporting tools to track business performance metrics.

<u>Skills: Python, Excel, Agile, SQL, Project Management, Tableau, Pyspark, Technical Solution Design, Enterprise Solution Design.</u>

2019-10 - 2020-05

Software Engineer

Menerva Software, Kochi, Kerala

Influencer Marketing - Social Media Analysis

- Worked with one of the Media Agency focusing on Influencer Marketing, Creative, Performance, Strategy and Integrated Marketing.
- Worked closely with client to design and develop robust solutions to analyses
 matrices like Engagement rate, Click-Through Rate, Impressions etc.. on
 social media data of Influencers to enhance marketing campaign strategy of big
 brands.
- It includes data collection from different social media platforms like Facebook, Instagram etc.., analysis of these data and design data models or logical solutions to evaluate data using python 3, SQL etc.
- Worked on segments of NLP like Sentiment Analysis using both Rule Based and ML based techniques (as part of RnD).
- Applied statistical and algebraic techniques to interpret key points from gathered data

Skills: Python, Py-data libraries, Scikit-learn(sklearn), Scipy, Excel

2018-06 - 2019-09

Software Engineer/Analyst

Qrech Global Solutions, Kazhakoottam, Kerala

QFT Financial ERP - Analyst

- Worked in decision-making role in product development phase of financial ERP product.
- Applied honed problem-solving skills to analyze and resolve issues impacting business operations and goal achievement.
- Performed gap analysis to identify areas of improvement.
- Improved business direction by prioritizing customers and implementing changes based on collected feedback.

QFT HR & Payroll - Frontend Developer

- Responsible for design, development and maintaining components of frontend components in Angular.
- Worked with Agile development tools like JIRA, Confluence, Git etc..

 Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance

Skills: Excel, Angular 2.0, JIRA, Confluence, Git, AWS

2017-05 - 2018-04 Technology Support Analyst

Moving Picture Company

- Worked in analysis of CG software to improve performance and request for enhancement of features
- Experience with migrating legacy code to Python 3
- Improved LLD of code base without affecting the functionalities and which improve the efficiency of system 2x times.

Skills: Python, Git, Linux

Certifications

2021-09 IBM Data Analyst Professional Certificate

2022-05 Agile Scrum Master (Simple Learn)

Education

2013-07 - 2017-05 Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science And Engineering

College of Engineerng Chengannur - Chengannur

· Graduated with 7.73 GPA

Professional Profile

- Https://www.hackerrank.com/gryptos
- Https://www.hackerearth.com/@gokulthottupuram
- Https://github.com/gryptos